<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Sir T.J.'s speech to his wife and children</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 4KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 3 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B43994</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">625106363</idno>
  <idno type="VID">211344</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240859588</idno>
  
            <idno type="OCLC"> 625106363</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocn 625106363</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing S3888</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B43994)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 211344)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English Books, 1641-1700 ; 2971:4)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Sir T.J.'s speech to his wife and children</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.)   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1685]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>In verse.</note>
                  <note>Place and date of publication suggested by Wing (2nd ed.).</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in: British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="topical_term">Ballads, English --  17th century --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="topical_term">English wit and humor --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="geographic_name">Great Britain --  History --  James II, 1685-1688 --  Poetry --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Broadsides --  England --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-07 </date>
            <label>Apex CoVantage</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-10 </date>
            <label>Anne Simpson </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-10 </date>
            <label>Anne Simpson</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="speech">
            <pb facs="tcp:211344:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:211344:2"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:211344:2"/>
            <head>Sir T. J's SPEECH TO HIS Wife and Children.</head>
            <lg n="1">
               <head>I.</head>
               <l>DEar Wife, let me have a good Fire made,</l>
               <l>I'll tell you such News will make you all glad,</l>
               <l>The like for another is scarce to be had.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>This it is to be Learned and Witty.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="2">
               <head>II.</head>
               <l>First, (Butler, do you a Glass of Wine bring,)</l>
               <l>I'll tell you all the great Love of my King,</l>
               <l>Which is a dainty, curious, fine thing.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>This it is,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="3">
               <head>III.</head>
               <l>A Wise Learned Serjeant at Law I was made,</l>
               <l>And a dainty fine Coif was put on my Head,</l>
               <l>Which is heavier far than a Hundred of Lead.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>This it is,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="4">
               <head>IV.</head>
               <l>But soon after this I was made the Recorder,</l>
               <l>To keep the Worshipful Rabble in order,</l>
               <l>And wore a red Gown with long Sleeves and Border.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>This it is,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="5">
               <head>V.</head>
               <l>What Justice I did, my dear Wife, you can tell;</l>
               <l>Right or wrong, I spar'd none, like the Devil in Hell;</l>
               <l>But, Guilty or not, I sent all to <hi>Bridewell.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>This it is,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="6">
               <head>VI.</head>
               <l>Unless it were those who greased my Fist,</l>
               <l>To them I gave license to cheat whom they list,</l>
               <l>(For 'twas only those my <hi>Mittimus</hi> miss'd.)</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>This it is,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="7">
               <head>VII.</head>
               <l>But then the King dy'd, which caused a pother;</l>
               <l>So I went to condole with the new King, his Brother,</l>
               <l>With <hi>Sorrow</hi> in one hand, and <hi>Grief</hi> in the other.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>This it is,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="8">
               <head>VIII.</head>
               <l>For an Ignorant Judge I was call'd by the King</l>
               <l>To the <hi>Chequer-Court,</hi> 'tis a wonderful thing,</l>
               <l>Of which in short time the whole Nation did ring.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>This it is to be Learned and Witty.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="9">
               <head>IX.</head>
               <l>By Great <hi>James</hi> I was rais'd to the <hi>Common-Pleas</hi> Bench,</l>
               <l>'Cause he saw I had exquisite Politick Sense,</l>
               <l>Which his Wisdom perceiv'd in the Future Tense.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>This it is,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="10">
               <head>X.</head>
               <l>At <hi>Sarum</hi> Five Hundred Pounds I have gotten,</l>
               <l>To save Malefactors from swinging in Cotten,</l>
               <l>For which they we hang'd, and now almost rotten.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>This it is,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="11">
               <head>XI.</head>
               <l>But now, my dear Love, comes the Cream of the Jest,</l>
               <l>For the King would take off the <hi>Oaths</hi> and the <hi>Test;</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Which I told all his People would be for the best.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>This it is,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="12">
               <head>XII.</head>
               <l>He had my Opinion, That 'twas in his Power</l>
               <l>To destroy all the Laws in less time than an hour,</l>
               <l>For which I may chance to be sent to the <hi>Tower.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>This it is,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="13">
               <head>XIII.</head>
               <l>And now to <hi>Magdalen-</hi>Colledge I come,</l>
               <l>Where we turn'd out most, but kept in some,</l>
               <l>That so a New Colledge of Priests might have room</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>This it is,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="14">
               <head>XIV.</head>
               <l>And so by that means we left the door ope,</l>
               <l>To turn out the Bishops, and let in the Pope,</l>
               <l>For which we have justly deserved a Rope.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>This it is to be Learned and Witty.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
            <pb facs="tcp:211344:3"/>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>